RG 004:134, Stafford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Stafford Probate Court records
1741-1979, bulk 1741-1935
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Stafford District)
47.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1759-1951; Probate files, 1741-1933; Marriage waivers, 1956-1979.
RG004_134
1912-009, 2011-002, 2013-049
Historical Note
Stafford, Tolland County, Town settled in 1719
The Stafford Probate District was constituted May 1759, from the Hartford and Pomfret Probate Districts. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Ellington, May 1786 - May 30, 1826 (covered "that part of town lying east of a median line drawn from the northwest corner of Tolland"; Somers, May 1759 - May 1826 and January 6, 1999 - January 4, 2011; Tolland, May 1759 - June 3, 1830; Union, May 1759 - January 4, 2011; Vernon, May 1814 - May 30, 1826; Willington, May 1759 - June 3, 1830. The Stafford Probate District merged with the Enfield Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the North Central Connecticut Probate District which serves the municipalities of Enfield, Somers, Stafford, and Union.
Town of Stafford, Probate District chronology:
1719 - May 1759, Hartford District
May 1759 - January 4, 2011, Stafford District
January 5, 2011 - Present, North Central Connecticut District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-34, 1759-1924; 4 volumes of bonds, 1868-1951; and 1 unnumbered volume, 1900-1921. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after 34. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1741-1933. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1741-1933 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accessions 2011-002 are numnbered 1 to 34. There is an unnumbered bond volume and three bond volumes numbered 3, 4, and 45. There is an unnumbered volume labeled "S" on the spine.
Probate files in accession 1912-009 are arranged alphabetically.
Marriage waivers in accession 2013-049 are arranged chronologically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-009 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Ellington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Somers; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stafford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Union; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Vernon; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Willington
Places:
Ellington (Conn.); Somers (Conn.); Stafford (Conn.); Tolland (Conn.); Union (Conn.); Vernon (Conn.); Willington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-002, Record books, 1759-1951, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-32, 1759-1930; probate files, 1741-1880 (Accession 1912-009); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-010 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 31, 1912 (1758-1875); October 3, 1914 (1741-1933); October 5, 1934 (1741-1933). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-002 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 7, 2010 and bonds volume 45 on August 5, 2014.
Container List
- Record books, 1759-1951; 22.5 cubic feet (41 volumes); 2011-002
  - Records, 1769-1777 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1759-1783 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1784-1791 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1791-1798 (Volume 4, Part 1)
    Part 1 contains pages 1-184
  - Records, 1791-1798 (Volume 4, Part 2)
    Part 2 contains pages 185-304 and 1A-173A
  - Records, 1800-1808 (Volume 5, Part 1)
    Part 1 contains pages 1-274
  - Records, 1800-1808 (Volume 5, Part 2)
    Part 2 contains pages 275-565
  - Records, 1790-1801 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1809-1812 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1812-1815 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1815-1816 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1817-1818 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1816-1823 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1821-1828 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1825-1830 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1829-1835 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1836-1842 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1842-1847 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1847-1852 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1851-1858 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1863-1876 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1876-1885 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1885-1892 (Volume 21)
  - Decrees, 1885-1899 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1891-1893 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1893-1895 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1896-1897 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1898-1909 (Volume 26)
  - Decrees, 1900-1908 (Volume 27)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1907-1908 (Volume 28)
  - Decrees, 1908-1918 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1904-1918 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1909-1913 (Volume 31)
  - Decrees, 1914-1930 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1916-1922 (Volume 33)
  - Decrees, 1919-1924 (Volume 34)
  - Bonds, 1868-1887 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1887-1905, 1914 (Volume 3)
  - Bonds, 1905-1935 (Volume 4)
  - Bonds, 1934-1951 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1900-1921 (Volume S)
- Probate files, 1741-1933, bulk 1759-1920; 25 cubic feet; 1912-009
  - Abbot - Aldrich (Drawer 1)
  - Allen - Ash (Drawer 2)
  - Ashley - Baldwin (Drawer 3)
  - Ballard - Beal (Drawer 4)
  - Beckwith - Bidwell (Drawer 5)
  - Billings - Bolton (Drawer 6)
  - Bond - Brooks, H. (Drawer 7)
  - Brooks, I. - Bugbee, H. (Drawer 8)
  - Bugbee, I. - Cady, E. (Drawer 9)
  - Cady, F. - Chadwick (Drawer 10)
  - Chaffee - Chapman, I. (Drawer 11)
  - Chapman, J. - Clary (Drawer 12)
  - Cleaveland - Collins (Drawer 13)
  - Colton - Converse, Julius (Drawer 14)
  - Converse, Julius - Corcoran (Drawer 15)
  - Costello - Cummings, E. (Drawer 16)
  - Cummings, F. - Davis, A. (Drawer 17)
  - Davis, B. - Delphia (Drawer 18)
  - Denison - Drake, P. (Drawer 19)
  - Drake, Q. - Eaton (Drawer 20)
  - Edgerton - Ellis, R. (Drawer 21)
  - Ellis, S. - Fenton, E. (Drawer 22)
  - Fenton, F. - Fisk, M. (Drawer 23)
  - Fisk, N. - Foster, N. (Drawer 24)
  - Foster, O. - Gardner (Drawer 25)
  - Gary - Goodale, G. (Drawer 26)
  - Goodale, H. - Griffiths (Drawer 27)
  - Griggs - Hammond, E. (Drawer 28)
  - Hammond, F. - Hatch, Joseph (Drawer 29)
  - Hatch, Judah - Hinkley (Drawer 30)
  - Hines - Holt, C. (Drawer 31)
  - Holt, D. - Howard, L. (Drawer 32)
  - Howard, M. - Hunt (Drawer 33)
  - Huntington - Hyde, M. (Drawer 34)
  - Hyde, N. - Jennings (Drawer 35)
  - Jensen - Johnson, J (Drawer 36)
  - Johnson, K. - Kelley (Drawer 37)
  - Kellogg - Kingsbury (Drawer 38)
  - Kinney - Larned (Drawer 39)
  - Lasbury - Leonard, H. (Drawer 40)
  - Leonard, I. - Lothrop, D. (Drawer 41)
  - Lothrop, E. - Lyon (Drawer 42)
  - MacCarter - Marcy, Calvin (Drawer 43)
  - Marcy, Charles - Mewer (Drawer 44)
  - Meyers - Morehouse (Drawer 45)
  - Morey - Needham, H. (Drawer 46)
  - Needham, I. - Norris, J. (Drawer 47)
  - Norris, K. - Orcutt (Drawer 48)
  - Organ - Parsons, L. (Drawer 49)
  - Parsons, M. - Paul (Drawer 50)
  - Paulk - Penniman (Drawer 51)
  - Percival - Pomeroy (Drawer 52)
  - Pool - Quimby (Drawer 53)
  - Rafftery - Risley (Drawer 54)
  - Rister -Root, E. (Drawer 55)
  - Root, F. - Sanford (Drawer 56)
  - Sanger - Sexton, C. (Drawer 57)
  - Sexton, D. - Sikes (Drawer 58)
  - Sikora - Smith, E. (Drawer 59)
  - Smith, F. - Sparks, J. (Drawer 60)
  - Sparks, K. - Starbuck (Drawer 61)
  - Stearns - Strong, E. (Drawer 62)
  - Strong, F. - Talcott (Drawer 63)
  - Tallman - Thrasher, J. (Drawer 64)
  - Thrasher, K. - Townsend (Drawer 65)
  - Tracy - Virgin (Drawer 66)
  - Wakefield - Walker, I. (Drawer 67)
  - Walker, J. - Wardwell, M. (Drawer 68)
  - Wardwell, N. - Waterhouse (Drawer 69)
  - Waters - West, R. (Drawer 70)
  - West, S. - White, L. (Drawer 71)
  - White, M. - Wilbur (Drawer 72)
  - Wilcox - Williams (Drawer 73)
  - Wilson - Woods (Drawer 74)
  - Woodward - Zanoli; Miscellaneous (Drawer 75)
- Inventory Control Book, 1741-1933; T003073
  Index of the three accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-009
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Marriage Waivers, 1956-1979; 2013-049
  - Marriage waivers, 1956-1979 (Box 1)